# Arnaud Bailly 26 avril 1969

www.linkedin.com/in/arnaudbailly • https://github.com/abailly 6, rue de Clermont · 44000 Nantes · France

# Summary

track record of delivering business-focused high-quality solutions quickly and efficiently. I have a wide array of skills and knowledge in anything software-related with a particular focus on software engineering, language design and implementation, functional programming, automated testing and DevOps.

ficient ways to develop distributed and de-focus on actual coding techniques rather than centralized applications and systems, particu- organisational tools.

I am an experienced technical lead, ar- larly looking into statically typed languageschitect and software engineer with a proven based solutions like Haskell or Idris. I also have an interest in maintaining existing applications, whether using legacy or brand-new technologies.

Strong team player and seasoned team leader, I am always on the look for better ways to collaboratively develop and maintain software stack, hence my decade-old interest in I currently focus on finding novel and ef- Agile development theory and practice with a

# **Work Experience**

Symbiont.io

New-York, USA (remote)

Jun 2018 – Dec 2019

# **Lead Software Engineer**

- Design and implement a fullstack loans management solution on top of Symbiont's Smart Contracts platform
- Hire and lead a distributed (USA, UK, France) team of engineers working in close collaboration with the product management team
- Deliver incrementally a working solution testable by the end-users, based on eXtreme Programming principles: Test-Driven Development, Pair and Mob Programming, Whole Team integration, Short feedback loops...
- Technology stack: eXtreme Programming, Custom Blockchain language, Typescript, React, GraphQL, Python, Haskell, Docker, Kubernetes

# **Senior Software Engineer**

*Jul* 2017 – May 2018

- Implement a key component of the platform responsible for the execution of a distributed ledger's atomic transactions.
- Coach the team getting up to speed on Haskell development eco-system and best practices, esp. regarding application architecture, property-based testing, components structuring...
- Design and develop a distributed model-based testing solution for the platform, inspired by Jepsen. This became the standard integration and system-level testing solution for the company. It defines a high-level Domain-Specific Language to describe the various actions available to clients and topology of the system.
- Technology stack: Haskell, Blockchain, Docker, Kubernetes, GCP, Microservices

GorillaSpace

Singapore (remote) Dec 2016 – Mar 2017

- Designed and implemented a prototype solution for office space marketplace enabling actors in the commercial property market to increase the yield of their spaces
- Technology stack: Haskell, Elm, Docker, GCP, AWS, Micro-services

## Capital Match

Singapore (remote)

### CTO and Co-Founder

Aug 2014 – Mar 2016

- Designed and grew the leading peer-to-peer lending platform in Singapore, managing S\$7.5M+ loans and 2K+ investors: Features included complete loan payment processing, emails alerting, bank reconciliation, profile and user's management, accounting...
- Designed and built infrastructure management software for secure and safe operations of the platform: continuous integration through self-hosted git push, automated build and deployment of docker-based services, version-controlled configuration management...
- Hired and managed a distributed team of 3 software engineers- Setup and facilitated lightweight kanban-style development process
- Use Haskell for most software in the stack, including custom event-sourced data storage, REST API, build and production infrastructure software- aggressive automation for provisioning and managing hosts, Riemann monitoring, digital ocean and AWS hosting
- Technology stack: Clojurescript, React, Haskell, Docker, Microservices

Murex Paris, France

#### Freelance Consultant

Jun 2016 – Jul 2016

As part of the R&D Team, I studied potential integration of several open-source distributed data streams processing tools within existing system.

- Survey of existing OSS platforms, most notably Spark eco-system
- Analysis of existing code and system's features and coding of exemplar use cases in Spark
- Suggestions for future improvements and integration roadmap.
- Technology stack: Java, Scala, Spark

### Solution Architect and Developer

Jun 2013 – Aug 2014

- I designed and developed a distributed solution based on REST principles and web technology to operate the MX.3 platform, providing a central configuration endpoint for orchestrating a multi-site MX.3 environment
- Exposes a REST API to start/stop services across a cluster and provide live feedback on startup/shutdown process and status
- Worked with Singapore team to implement the solution for real customers and helped making it live in production
- **Tech stack**: Java, REST API, Docker, Jenkins

#### Senior Developer & Consultant

*Sep* 2012 – *May* 2013

As member of cross-functional team, I help functional teams and project improve their software development process, coding and designing in Java. I also work on proposing global best practices and standardizing key components and practices to improve velocity and quality of developments.

#### Senior Developer & Architect

May 2010 – Sep 2011

Lead developer for performance improvement, code cleaning and scalability

- Member of a team of 10+ people, working on a middleware platform for Murex
- Core developer for the platform, involved in evolving the architecture and design to ensure and maintain production-quality software, including build engineering, release engineering, backlog and roadmap maintenance

### Agile Enabler

Jun 2009 – Apr 2010

- Within a team of 4 people, help Murex' software developers community reduce lead-time and defects by applying "modern" software development techniques and tools: eXtreme Programming, Lean, TDD, and provide services and tools to help them improve their development effort(reduce lead-time, reduce defects)
- Introduced and help spread Test Driven-Development, Pair Programming, BDD and various XP/Agile techniques
- Work on improving build system (cross-platform mixed C/C++/Java)
- **Technology stack**: Java, C/C++, Jenkins, Oracle

PolySpot

Lead Developer & Architect

Paris, France

Sep 2011 – Aug 2012

- I lead a small team of developers working on a component part of the next major release of PolySpot's product, PolySpot Enterprise Search.
- This component is responsible for storing metadata of documents and managing transformation, indexation and querying over this large dataset
- Technical stack: Java, MongoDB, Akka, NLP

OQube Lille, France

**Consultant** *Jun* 2006 – *Jan* 2010

I provided consulting services, short term, long term, part-time or full-time to help improve software engineering practices with a strong Agile / XP slant, mostly in an open source Java/J2EE environment, including:

- XP coaching / mentoring and technical leadership- code and design practices and training
- XP tools and techniques setup and training: Test-driven development, continuous integration, pair programming, incremental design, automate acceptance testing
- prototyping and exploratory development

Courtanet

Paris, France

Coach & Architect

Apr 208 – Mar 2009

- Part of R&D team developing an insurance policy comparison platform
- Coached a team of 6 engineers on Agile software development practices: Test and Behaviour driven development, continuous integration and continuous delivery, iterative planning...
- Technology stack: Javascript, Java, XUL

Norsys

Lille, France

Research Engineer

Sep 2001 – Mar 2006

During my PhD thesis, I took part in various prototype and proof-of-concepts projects for several customers:

- Implementation of a mobile (WAP) commercial website of a retail company
- Code analysis and generation for reimplementation in Java of a legacy application
- Design and implementation of asynchronous message-passing platform for batch processing

- Training and coaching of developers teams in testing, continuous integration
- Implementation of software quality analysis tools

# Sans Peur et Sans Reproche

Lille, France

**Co-Founder** 

Apr 1994 – Dec 1997

- Founded Role Playing Game and Boardgame publishing company with 3 friends
- Managed print publishing process, relationship with printers, technical infrastructure and software for professional publishing- Took part in writing, editing, typesetting all our products
- Coded a Point-of-Sale management software for our RPG shop

### Crédit Agricole

Lille, France

### **Account Manager**

Feb 1991 – Mar 1994

Within the Small Businesses Department of a regional retail bank, I managed a portfolio of about 60 customers, dealing with all the aspects of business banking: Loan underwriting, treasury, delinquent loans recovery...

#### Education

Université des Sciences et Technologies de Lille

Lille, France

PHD, Computer Science

Sep 2001 – Sep 2005

Thesis subject: *Test and Validation of Component Software* **MsC, Computer Science** 

Sep 1998 – Jun 2001

SKEMA Business School

Lille, France

Master, Business administration

Sep 1987 – Sep 1990

#### Skills

**Technical expertise:** Over the years, I have accumulated experience and knowledge on a wide array of fields related to software architecting, engineering and development, with a bias towards hands-on coding excellence.

- Software design and implementation: Strong emphasis on testing, e.g. Test-Driven Development, System-level testing, Property and Model-Based Testing, Test cases generation, Behaviour Driven Development to foster business-developers collaboration (FitNesse, Cucumber); Distributed Systems design and implementation
- *Agile software development practices*: eXtreme Programming, Scrum, Continuous integration processes and tools, Domain-Driven Design
- Functional Programming: Haskell, Idris, Elm, Clojure, Scala, OCaml
- Object-Oriented Programming: Java, a bit of C++ and .Net, Design Patterns, UML
- Web technologies: Solid knowledge of HTTP, HTML, CSS, REST APIs, Javascript-based programming (React/Redux, Clojurescript, Typescript)
- Cloud technologies: (Docker, GCP, DigitalOcean, Azure, AWS, DevOps)

**Natural languages:** French (*mother tongue*), English (*full professional proficiency*), Spanish (*rusty*), □□ (*beginner*)

#### **Interests**

**Non-exhaustive list, in random order:** philosophy (esp. philosophy of the mind and phenomenology), sociology, literature (french, russian classics), art (modern and contemporary), sport (mostly to stay fit), coding and programming, (un)conferences on software, cooking...